The battle for eternity begins
Gods of Egypt is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Alex Proyas.
A common thief joins a mythical god on a quest through Egypt.
Horus, played by Nikolaj Coster-Waldau.
Bek, played by Brenton Thwaites.
Set, played by Gerard Butler.
Thoth, played by Chadwick Boseman.
Hathor, played by Élodie Yung.
Zaya, played by Courtney Eaton.
Gods of Egypt is a 2016 fantasy action film directed by Alex Proyas
based on a fantastical version of ancient Egyptian deities.
It stars Nikolaj Coster-Waldau, Brenton Thwaites, Chadwick Boseman, Élodie Yung,
Courtney Eaton, Rufus Sewell, Gerard Butler and Geoffrey Rush.
The film follows the Egyptian god Horus, who partners with a mortal Egyptian
thief, on a quest to rescue his love and to save the world from Set.
Filming took place in Australia under the film production and distribution company Summit Entertainment in
conjunction with Thunder Road Pictures and Proyas' production company Mystery Clock Cinema.
While the film's production budget was $140 million, the parent company Lionsgate's financial
exposure was less than $10 million because of tax incentives and pre-sales.
The Australian government provided a tax credit for 46% of the film's budget.
When Lionsgate began promoting the film in November 2015, it received
backlash for its predominantly white cast playing Egyptian deities.
In response, Lionsgate and director Proyas apologized
for their ethnically-inaccurate casting.
Lionsgate released Gods of Egypt in theaters globally, starting on February 25, 2016, in 2D, RealD 3D,
and IMAX 3D, and in the United States, Canada, and 68 other markets on February 26.
It received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed a total of $150.7 million against a
$140 million budget, becoming a box office bomb and losing $90 million for Lionsgate.
It received five nominations at the 37th Golden Raspberry Awards.
The film explores themes of rescue, egypt, fight, nile, mythology.